[ Music ]
[ 音乐 ]
&gt;&gt; Good morning, everyone.
&gt;&gt; 大家早上好
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
Wow.
哇 谢谢
Welcome to Advanced Dark Mode.
欢迎来到升级版的深色模式
I'm Matt Jacobson.
我是 Matt Jacobson
I'll be joined later on stage by
我的同事 Jeff Nadeau
my colleague, Jeff Nadeau.
一会儿也会上台来
We're engineers in the Cocoa
我们都是 Apple Cocoa 框架团队的工程师
We are super excited to talk to
我今天非常激动能够
you today about the awesome Dark
与你们谈谈 Mojave 里
Mode in Mojave.
超赞的深色模式
Now, in the intro session
你们已经
yesterday, you learned all the
从昨天的介绍会上
things you need to get started
了解了如何
adapting your app for Dark Mode,
将你的 App 改为深色模式
like rebuilding on the macOS
比如在 macOS 10.14 SDK
10.14 SDK.
上对 App 进行重建
Making use of dynamic colors
使用动态色彩
instead of static or hardcoded
来代替静态或硬编码色彩
Making correct use of template
正确使用模板图像和素材
And, most of all, making use of
最重要的是
the new features in Xcode 10 to
利用 Xcode 10 的新功能
define custom color and image
来定义深色模式专用的
assets specifically for Dark
自定义颜色和图像素材
Now, if you need a review on any
如果你需要再回顾一下
of those topics, I highly
这些话题 那么我十分推荐
recommend going back and
你之后再去
watching the intro session on
看看昨天介绍会的视频
Now, most UI will look great in
只需利用那些技巧
Dark Mode using just those
大多数 UI 在深色模式中
techniques.
就会看起来很棒
In fact, some of our system apps
其实 我们的一些系统 App
required no other changes.
并不需要额外的改变 这非常好
But we know some cases will
但在某些情况下
require a little bit more work
只凭那些技巧还不够
and that's what we're going to
这就是我们
get into in this session.
在这场会上要讲的内容
We're going to cover six main
今天我们将涵盖六个主要的方面
First, the appearance system,
首先是外观系统
how it works, and how you can
它是怎样运作的
make use of it in your custom
要如何在自定义视图里使用它
Second, materials, what they
第二是素材 什么是素材
are, and how you can best make
如何才能在你的 UI 里
use of them in your UI.
充分利用它
Then I'll hand it over to Jeff
接下来的部分由 Jeff 介绍
and he'll talk about vibrant
他将谈谈 “Vibrant Blending（动态混合）”
blending, which is an awesome
这种方法很棒
way to make your views look
会让你的视图看起来更好
As well as reacting correctly to
他还会讲到用一些
selection using something called
叫做背景风格的东西
background style.
对选择做出正确的反应
Finally, he'll wrap it up with
最后 他会综合起来
some discussion on how to back
说说如何
deploy your app to older
当你在旧的 macOS 版本上
versions of macOS while still
使用你的 App 时
supporting Dark Mode, as well as
仍然能支持深色模式
some general tips and tricks for
还有一些小技巧和方法
polishing your apps for Dark
来帮你改进 App 的深色模式
All right.
好了
Let's get started.
我们开始吧
So, in Mojave, your app will
在 Mojave 中 你的 App
need to look great in light and
无论在浅色还是深色模式都要看起来很棒
And the way you'll do that is
这个时候你就要
using something called
用到一个叫做
NSAppearance.
NSAppearance 的东西
NSAppearance is the theme system
NSAppearance 是整个 Cocoa 都在
used throughout Cocoa and the
使用的主题系统
key part about it is you only
关键是你只需要
have to maintain a single view
保持一个单一的视图层级
hierarchy and NSAppearance will
NSAppearance 就会让你的 App
help it look great in light and
在浅色和深色模式中都很好看
Now, in addition to being at the
好了 除了用作深色模式的核心外
core of Dark Mode, we've already
我们已经使用
been using NSAppearance for
NSAppearance 好几年了
several years and it's underlied
同时它还是一些特性的基础
high contrast mode of macOS as
如 macOS 的高对比度模式
well as the touch bar UI
以及为触控栏
designed specifically for that
这个出色的硬件
awesome piece of hardware.
设计的 UI
Now, previously we've had one
我们先前已经有了一个主要外观
main appearance, one main light
为 Aqua 窗口
appearance for aqua windows and
准备的浅色外观
we called aqua.
叫做 Aqua
And, of course, in 10.14, we're
当然 在 10.14 里
introducing a second appearance
我们要引入一种新的外观
for aqua windows for Dark Mode
用于深色模式下的 Aqua 窗口
called darkAqua.
叫做 darkAqua
These objects contain all the
这些对象包括所有
assets that views draw with.
视图绘制所需的素材
So, any time you use system
因此 只要你使用
dynamic colors or standard
系统动态色彩
effects or named images or even
标准效果 或已命名的图像
just standard Cocoa controls,
甚至只是标准的 Cocoa 控件
this is where all that stuff is
这些对象都会为你提供素材
And AppKit will automatically
只要你关联了 macOS 10.14 SDK
provide appearances for all of
AppKit 就会自动地
you views and windows based on
基于系统偏好设置里
the user's light/dark preference
用户对浅色或深色的选择
in system preferences once you
为你所有的视图和窗口
link on the macOS 10.14 SDK.
提供相应外观
So, here's our beautiful
这是我们可爱的
Chameleon Wrangler app that
《Chameleon Wrangler》App
Rachel and Taylor created in the
是 Rachel 和 Taylor
intro session and you can see
在之前的介绍会中创建的
once we linked it on the macOS
你可以看到 如果我们将它与 macOS 10.14
10.14 SDK, AppKit went ahead and
SDK 关联  AppKit 就会开始运行
automatically gave it the
并自动给它设置
darkAqua appearance.
darkAqua 外观
Now, that's great, but what if
这样很好 但如果
we want to change the
我们想要改变外观呢
For example, what if we wanted
比如说 我们想要改变
to change the appearance of this
这个笔记的视图
We might think that in the dark
在深色的外观下
appearance we still might want
我们也许想要让
the notes view to appear light.
笔记的视图仍然是浅色的
Well, you can do that using
这时 你就可以利用
NSAppearanceCustomization.
NSAppearanceCustomization
Now, this is a protocol, but
这是一个协议
it's not a protocol you have to
但它不是那种需要
go off and adopt in your
你在 App 中应用的协议
It's already adopted by NSView
它已在 NSView 和 NSWindow 中应用了
and NSWindow and, in Mojave,
在 Mojave 中
NSApplication conforms as well.
NSApplication 也会遵循这个协议
It's a pretty simple protocol.
它是个相当简单的协议
It just adds two properties.
只添加了两项属性
First property is appearance and
第一是 appearance
this is where you can override
这里你可以重写
the appearance for a particular
一个特定对象的外观
Now, it's an optional
它是一个可选择的 NSAppearance
NSAppearance because, if you set
因为如果你将它的参数
it to nil, the object will
设置为 “nil” 那么
simply inherit its appearance
该对象只会继承
from its ancestors.
父对象的外观
There's also effective
第二个是 effectiveAppearance
appearance and this is a
这是一个
read-only property that you can
只读属性
use to find out what appearance
你可以用它来找到一个视图
a view will draw with.
会用什么外观来绘制
And of course, to use this,
当然 要利用这个
you'll have to get the right
你得有个正确的
NSAppearance object and you can
NSAppearance 对象
do that pretty easily using the
你可以用 NSAppearance 中的
NSAppearance named initializer.
named: 初始化语句来轻松完成
Just pass aqua or darkAqua based
根据你想要的外观
on which appearance you want and
只要传入“.aqua”或“.darkAqua”
then you can go ahead and just
你就能继续
assign that to the appearance
将其指定为
property of the object that
所要定制的对象的
you'd like to customize.
外观属性
So, in this case, we'll assign
在这个例子中
the aqua appearance to the
我们将指定 Aqua 外观
appearance property of the text
给 textView 的外观属性
view and now it uses the light
现在 它就变成浅色外观了
All right.
好的 这个很简单 所以
take a look at another case.
我们来看下一种情况
You might have a window that
你可能会有一个窗口
kind of hangs off of a
像这样悬浮在某个
particular view.
特定视图下
And you probably want its
你可能想要
appearance to match the view it
将它的外观与其所在的视图
hangs off of.
保持一致
Now, we could just assign the
那么 我们可以直接指定
aqua appearance to this window
Aqua 外观给这个窗口
just like we did to the view,
就像刚刚那样
but what we really want is
但是 我们真正想要的
something a little stronger.
不仅如此
We want its appearance to
我们想要它
inherit from the view and we can
继承视图中的外观 我们
do that-- first of all, AppKit
就可以这样做 首先 AppKit
will automatically do this for
会自动地在一些常用窗口中
us for a number of common
继承视图的外观
windows, like menus, popovers,
如菜单 弹出框
tool tips, and sheets, so you
工具提示和工作表
don't have to worry about it in
因此你不需要担心这些窗口
But, for custom cases like this,
但是 对于这样的自定义窗口
there's new API in Mojave that
在 Mojave 中有一个新的 API
you can use to do this.
可以供你使用
It's called Appearance Source.
叫做 appearanceSource
Now, this is a property that
这是一种
takes any object that conforms
能使任何对象都遵循
to that
NSAppearanceCustomization 协议的属性
protocol-- so, views and
包括视图和窗口
windows-- and you just assign it
你只要为其指定
to the appearanceSource property
appearanceSource 属性
and the window will inherit its
该窗口就会从该对象中
appearance from that object.
继承视图的外观
So, in this case, we'll assign
那么 在这里 我们将 testView
the text view to the
指定到该子窗口的
appearanceSource property of
appearanceSource 属性
that child window and now it's
这样一来
appearance will always inherit
textView 的外观就会
from that view no matter what it
一直继承该视图的外观
In fact, you should think of the
其实 你可以将外观系统
appearance system as a sort of
想象成一种层级结构
Similar to the view hierarchy
与你可能比较熟悉的
you're probably familiar with,
视图层级类似
but extending to windows and the
但要将其扩展到窗口
application as well.
以及 App
And when we ask AppKit for a
当我们要求 AppKit 给出一个
view's effective appearance,
视图的有效外观时
AppKit will simply walk up this
AppKit 就会沿着这个
hierarchy until it finds an
层级结构走下去
object with a specified
直到找到一个
appearance and that's the
有具体外观的对象
appearance we'll use.
那便是我们使用的外观
OK.
好 现在 我们知道了对象如何
get an appearance and how the
获得外观 以及外观系统
appearance system works, let's
是如何运作的
talk about how you can use it in
下面我们就来谈谈如何在你的
your custom views and controls.
自定义视图和控件中使用它
Here's an example.
举个例子
Let's say I wanted this custom
如果我想要让这个
header view here to use a
自定标头视图
different color in light and
在浅色和深色的外观下
dark appearance.
使用不同的颜色
Now, we already know in Xcode 10
现在 我们已经知道在 Xcode 10 里
I can go into the asset catalog
我可以进入素材目录编辑器
editor and specify specific
为浅色或暗色主题
color assets for light and dark.
设置特定的色彩素材
But then how do I use that in my
但怎样在我的自定视图中使用它呢
Well, here's one way that seems
好 下面我要演示的这个方法
tempting but won't work and I'll
看起来很靠谱 但其实行不通
show you why.
我会告诉你为什么
First, we'll add an NSColor
首先 我们将给我们的视图
property to our view.
添加一个 NSColor 属性
And in init, we'll use that
初始化状态下 我们将用该颜色
color to populate our layer.
填充我们的图层
And if the color changes, we'll
而如果颜色改变了
go ahead and update our layer
我们也将开始更新相应的图层
Let's try that out.
让我们来试试
OK. It looks pretty good in
好 在浅色模式下看起来很好
light, but if we switch to dark,
但是如果我们转为暗的状态
we can see our color didn't
就能看到我们的颜色其实
actually change.
并没有改变
And that's because even though
这是因为即使
our NSColor is dynamic, the CG
我们的 NSColor 是动态的
color that we get from it is
所得到的 cgColor 也是静态的
static.
它不会随外观而改变
And, since we configured our
因为我们在初始化程序段中
layer in our initializer, we
已经设置了图层
didn't get a chance to run any
那么在外观改变时
code when the appearance
我们无法运行任何代码
Now, the key takeaway from this
重点就是
is you need to do your
要把你随外观改变的内容
appearance sensitive work in
放到特定的区域
Specifically, the update
具体来说 就是使用 NSView 中的
constraints, layout, draw, and
updateConstraints() layout() draw()
update layer methods of NSView.
以及 updateLayer() 方法
Now, AppKit will automatically
这样的话 当外观改变时
call these methods as needed
如有需要 AppKit 就会自动
when the appearance changes.
调用这些方法
And if you need to trigger them
如果你需要手动地
manually, of course you can
触发它们 你当然可以一直使用
needsUpdateConstraints,
needsUpdateConstraints
needsLayout, and
needsLayout
needsDisplayProperties and
和 needsDisplay 这些属性
AppKit will automatically call
AppKit 会自动调用它们
them.
好 现在回到我们的例子
Instead of overriding init,
与其重写 init
we'll implement updateLayer and
我们可以执行 updateLayer()
there we can go ahead and safely
接着 就可以放心地通过
populate our layer by asking our
向我们的 NSColor 请求一个 cgColor
NSColor for a CG color.
来填充我们的图层
And if our color changes,
如果只有颜色变了
instead of updating our layer
而那里的图层却没有更新
right there, we'll just set the
我们就只需要将
needsDisplay property to true.
needsDisplay 属性设置为真
AppKit will come back around
AppKit 会自动回来并调用
updateLayer.
updateLayer()
So, let's run it again.
好 现在再看
Still looks good in light.
在浅色的状态仍然看起来很好
And now it uses the correct
现在 在深色的状态下
color in dark just like we
它的颜色正如我们所愿
wanted, so that's great.
效果很棒
Now, what if we want to do
好 如果我们想
something a little more
做一些更复杂的东西怎么办
complicated that might not be
如果仅仅用
expressible just with dynamic
动态色彩或者图像
colors or images?
可能不太容易表达
For example, maybe I would like
例如 也许我想要
to add this nice white glow
在 Chloe 美丽的脸庞后
behind Chloe's beautiful face
加点这种白色的光晕
here, but only in Dark Mode.
但只是在深色模式下我会怎么做呢
Well, for cases like that, we
好 这种情况下
have new API in Mojave that you
我们在 Mojave 中会有新的 API
can use to match against your
你可以用它来与你的
view's appearance.
视图外观相比对
Let me show you how it works.
我来示范一下
So, in this view, I'll override
在这个视图下
the layout method and I'll
我会重写 layout() 方法 并开启
switch on effectiveAppearance
effectiveAppearance.bestMatch(from:)
bestMatch(from:, I'll pass an
我会通过一个数组
array with all of the appearance
该数组有我的视图
names that my view happens to
所知道的全部外观的名字
know about.
在这里是 Aqua 和 darkAqua
Then it's just a matter of
接着就只需要
implementing behavior for each
给这些外观一一执行动作了
So, for the aqua appearance,
那么 对于 Aqua 外观
I'll simply use my imageView
我会只把我含有 Chole 大头照的
with Chloe's face as a subview.
imageView 作为一个子视图
And for darkAqua, I'll not only
而对于 darkAqua 外观 我不仅
use that imageView, but I'll
要用 imageView
also through my glowView behind
还要在后面加上 glowView
Finally, I'll implement a
最后 我会执行一个默认 case
default case and this is for
这是为了我的视图
appearances my view doesn't know
所不了解的默认外观而设
about and that includes
包括将来 Apple
might come out with in the
可能发布的外观
OK.
好的 让我们看看现在
looks like.
看起来怎么样
So, there it is in light, no
现在 是浅色的外观下
glow, that's what we wanted.
没有光晕 是我们想要的
Switch to dark and we have that
切换到深色外观
glow.
就有光晕了
That's great.
很好 好的
Let's talk for a minute about
下面让我们谈谈
high contrast.
高对比度
So, I said before that we've
我之前说过
been using NSAppearance for the
我们已经将 NSAppearance
high contrast mode of macOS.
用作 macOS 的高对比度模式了
And one of the nice side effects
为了支持深色模式
of doing all this work to
所做的一切
support Dark Mode is it makes it
带来的好处之一就是
really easy to support high
让支持高对比度
contrast really well as well.
变得十分容易
As a reminder, high contrast is
提醒一下 高对比度是
enabled through the increase
通过勾选系统偏好设置里的
contrast checkbox in system
“提高对比度”复选框来实现的
And in this mode, colors are
在这种模式下 色彩改变了
changed so that control bounds
所以控件边界
and other kinds of boundaries
和其他各种边界
are more easy to see.
都更容易看到
Now, in this mode, AppKit
现在 这种模式下
automatically replaces the aqua
AppKit 会自动将 Aqua
and darkAqua appearances with
和 darkAqua 外观替换为
high contrast counterparts.
高对比度外观
Now, these high contrast
而这些高对比度外观
appearances inherit from their
继承了他们的
normal contrast versions.
正常对比度的版本
So, what that means is any code
那么 这就意味着
you've written to take advantage
你所编写的任何利用
of Dark Mode will automatically
深色模式的代码
apply in high contrast Dark
都会自动适用于
Mode.
高对比度的深色模式
But you can go even further.
但你还可以更进一步
In Xcode 10, if you check this
在 Xcode 10 中
high contrast checkbox in the
如果你在素材目录编辑器中选中
asset catalog editor, it'll
这个 “High Contrast（高对比度）”复选框
allow you to specify color and
你可以特别为该外观的
image assets specifically for
高对比度版本
the high contrast versions of
指定颜色和图像素材
Now, you can also use those
你也可以在代码中使用
appearance names in code.
那些外观的名字
You might be temped to think,
你也许会忍不住想
well, great, I'll just pass them
唔 很好 我只要把它们传入
to NSAppearance themed and I'll
NSAppearance 主题就好了
get the NSAppearance object and
然后我会获得 NSAppearance 对象
I'll do something with that, but
再继续做点什么 但这行不通
Those appearances are only
那些外观
available through system
只在系统偏好设置中可用
But what you can do is pass them
而你能做的是把它们
to bestMatch(from:) just like we
传给 bestMatch(from:)
did before for Dark Mode to
像之前我们在深色模式做的那样
implement custom programmatic
执行自定义编程行为
OK.
好的 我们再来说说子图层
I know a lot of you out there
我知道你们许多人
have views that manage their own
都有管理着子图层的视图
important things to be aware of
我们要注意 关于深色模式的
for Dark Mode.
一些很重要的东西
Primarily, you need to know that
首先 你需要知道
custom sublayers will not
自定义子图层不会
inherit your view's appearance
自动继承你的视图的外观
Now, the easiest fix for this is
现在 最简单的修补方法
to switch them from being
就是将他们从子图层
sublayers to subviews.
转换为子视图
If you do that, AppKit will
如果这么做了 那么 AppKit 就会
automatically handle the
自动处理
appearance inheritance for those
那些视图的外观继承
views, just like any other view.
就像其他视图一样
Otherwise, you'll have to manage
否则 你就必须
those layers manually using a
手动管理那些图层
couple techniques that I'll talk
用几种我下面提到的技巧
about now, viewDidChange
viewDidChangeEffectiveAppearance()
concept of the current
以及代表当前外观的
appearance.
NSAppearance.current
So, first viewDidChange
好 先是 viewDidChange
EffectiveAppearance.
EffectiveAppearance()
This is a new method on NSView
这是一种 NSView 中的新方法
that you can override to find
你可以进行重写来发现
out when your view's effective
视图的有效外观
appearance changes.
什么时候发生改变
Now, this is a good time to
这是执行所有
perform any custom invalidation
可能需要的
you might need to do or drop any
自定义禁用或释放
caches that are no longer
任何不再相关的缓存的好时机
But remember you don't need to
但是记住 你不需要
invalidate the view itself here,
使这里的视图本身失效
AppKit will do that for you
AppKit 会自动为你完成这点
Second, the concept of the
第二点 “当前外观”的概念
Now, this is a thread local
现在 这是一个线程局部变量
variable that you can access
你可以通过一个
through a class property on
NSAppearance 上的类属性来访问
If you're familiar with concepts
如果你比较熟悉
like the current NSGraphics
如 NSGraphicsContext.current
context or the current
或 NSProgress.current 这样的概念
NSProgress, you already know
你就已经明白了
what I'm talking about.
我在说什么
If not, just remember that this
如果你不熟悉 只要记住
is the appearance used to
这是用作解决
resolve dynamic colors and
动态色彩和图片的外观
AppKit will set up the current
AppKit 会在我们调用那些
appearance automatically for you
我们之前所说的
before we call any of those
特殊的 NSView 方法之前
special NSView methods we talked
自动为你
about before, like
建立当前外观
updateConstraints, layout, draw,
如 updateConstraints() layout() draw()
and updateLayer, but you can
以及 updateLayer() 方法 但你也可以
also set it up yourself where
在必要时
necessary and let's take a look
自己进行建立
at an example why you might do
那我们来看一个例子
that.
说明你为什么可能这样做
So, here's a custom that
好 这是一个包括了
maintains some sublayers.
一些子图层的自定义视图
I'll override this new
我会重写这个新的
viewDidChange
viewDidChange
EffectiveAppearance method and
EffectiveAppearance() 方法
I'll set my sublayer
再给我的子图层设置
needsDisplay.
NeedsDisplay()
Now, if I didn't do this, my
而如果我没有进行这些设置
sublayer wouldn't update when my
我的子图层不会随着
view's effective appearance
视图的有效外观的变化而更新
It would just stay the same.
它只会保持原样
And then in my layer delegate
接着在我的图层委托子程序里
routine, I'll save off the
我会保存当前外观
current appearance for later and
以备之后使用
then I'll go ahead and set the
接着我会继续
current appearance to my view's
把我的当前外观
effective appearance.
设置成 effectiveAppearance
Then I can go ahead and update
然后我就可以继续更新我的图层了
Now, if I hadn't set the current
这时 如果我之前没有
appearance before this, this
设置当前外观
code wouldn't be using my view's
那这个代码就不会使用
appearance and so it would end
我视图的外观 那样看起来
up looking wrong.
就不对了
Finally, when I'm done, I'll
最后 到这一步 我只要
just restore the old current
还原先前的当前外观
Here's another thing to be aware
如果你在管理图层的话
of if you're managing layers.
这里还需要注意一点
You might have code that looks
你或许已经有一些
like one of these two examples.
看起来像之前两个例子之一
Either you're setting the
要么你要将
contents of a layer to an
一个图层的内容设置为
NSImage or you're using the
某个 NSImage 要么你就要使用
layer contents for content scale
layerContents(forContentsScale:) API
API to create layer contents
来用某个图像为你的图层
from an image for your layer.
创建一个 layer.contents
If you have code like this, you
如果你有这样的代码
should know that the image will
你要知道图像不会
not automatically inherit the
自动继承外观
As before, the best fix is to
像之前一样 最好的修补方法就是
switch to views.
把它切换成视图
In this case, NSImageView.
在这里要用 NSImageView
NSImageView will take care of
NSImageView 会自动处理到
this detail as well as a bunch
这个细节 包括许多其他细节
of others automatically, so do
因此你最好这么做
Otherwise, you'll need to create
否则 你就要为你的图层
a CGImage from your NSImage for
从 NSImage 中
your layer.
创建一个 CGImage
And you'll do that using the
这时 你需要用
cgImage(forProposedRect:,
NSImage 中的 cgImage(forProposedRect:
context:, hints: API on NSImage.
context: hints:) API
And you'll have to be careful to
同时 你要注意
do this at a point where the
应该在当前外观正确的时候
current appearance is correct.
来做这件事情
So, a good place to do it is in
因此 最好在你的 updateLayer() 方法里
your updateLayer method.
完成这些
All right, so that's appearance.
好了 这就是外观
Now let's talk about materials.
下面我们来谈谈素材
Now, you've probably heard that
好 你大概已经听过
materials are one of the
素材是现在
building blocks of the modern
Mac UI 的一个重要部分
Mac UI, but you may have
但你也许有过疑惑
wondered to yourself, well, what
素材究竟是什么
start with a definition.
那么我就从它的定义开始
Materials are dynamic
素材是使用
backgrounds that make use of
一些效果的动态背景
effects like blurs, gradient,
比如模糊 渐变
tinting, translucency, and they
着色和半透明
provide a sense of depth or
它们为你的 UI 提供
context to your UI, as well as
深度 环境
just a bit of added beauty.
同时还有点美化作用
Here's a pretty typical Mac
这是一个相当典型的 Mac 桌面
desktop and you can see all the
你可以看到我们使用了
different places where we're
这些素材效果的
using these material effects--
所有的地方
actually, this isn't even all of
而其实 这些不是全部
Now, AppKit automatically
现在 AppKit 会自动地
provides materials in a number
为一些常见的地方
of common places, like the title
提供素材 如标题栏
bars and backgrounds of windows,
窗口背景
table views, sidebars, popovers,
表格视图 侧边栏 弹出框
menus, and even other places as
以及菜单 还有其他的地方
well.
但你也可以自己创建一种素材
yourself and add it to your UI
并将其添加到你的 UI 中
using a view called
这就要用到一种视图
NSVisualEffectView.
叫作 NSVisualEffectView
If you're not familiar with
如果你不熟悉它 很简单
simply, it's a view that shows a
它是一种显示素材的视图
And if you want to use one,
如果你想使用这种视图
you'll need to be aware of three
你要注意三个
main properties that you'll have
需要设置的主要属性
to set up and I'll go through
而我将依次地进行介绍
The state, blendingMode, and
包括 state blendingMode
material properties.
和 material
So, first, the state property.
首先是 state 属性
This controls whether the
它决定了素材
material uses the active window
是否使用活动窗口外观
Now, by default, the material
默认情况下
will just match its containing
素材会匹配包含它的窗口
window and so when that window
当这个窗口活动时
is active it'll look active.
素材也会看起来出于活动状态
When the window's inactive, the
当窗口不活动时
material will look inactive.
素材也会不活动
But you can also specify this
但是你也可以将
specifically to be active or
特定的部分指定为活动或不活动
inactive if you'd like to
如果你想要
control it manually.
手动控制的话
Second, the blendingMode
第二个 blendingMode 属性
This property controls whether
这个属性控制着
the material punches through the
素材是否会穿透
back of the window.
窗口的背后
Let me show you what I mean by
下面我来给你演示一下
Here's a preview using two
这是“预览” App 用了两种
different materials.
不同的素材
For one, this title bar
一个是 这个标题栏素材
material, if we peel it back, we
如果我们把它掀开
can see that it's blending the
就能看到它混合了
contents within the window,
窗口里的内容
including that color image
包括里面的彩色图像
So, it's not punching through
所以 它没有穿透到
the back of the window.
窗口的后面
There's also the sidebar
这是一个侧边栏素材
material and if we peel it back
如果我们将它掀开
we can see it's blurring the
我们就能看到它将
contents behind the window, so
窗口后面的内容模糊了
it's punching through the back
所以穿透到了窗口后面
so it can see to the windows
因而它可以看到
behind it as well as the
其背后的窗口 还有桌面
So, by default, a visual effect
好的 默认情况下 一个视觉效果视图
view will be in behind window
将会处于穿透窗口模式
mode, but you can control that
但你可以用
using the blendingMode property.
blendingMode 属性来控制它
Finally, the material property.
最后是 material 属性
This property encapsulates the
该属性封装了
material effect definition.
对素材效果的定义
What do I mean by that?
这是什么意思呢
That means the exact recipe of
也就是模糊 半透明
blur, translucency, gradience,
渐变以及着色的具体方法
tinting-- that all depends on
这些都取决于
the material property.
material 属性
Now, when we first started using
现在 我们先开始在
materials in Yosemite, we had
Yosemite 里使用素材时
two main materials, the light
我们有两种主要素材
and dark materials, and those
一种浅色的 一种深色的
served us really well at the
开始这两种素材很好用
time, but since then we've
但之后我们已经
really expanded our use of
扩大了系统中
materials across the system.
素材的使用
And now with Dark Mode, it no
那么在深色模式中
longer really makes sense to
仅仅指定一种素材为亮或暗
specify a material just as light
不再具有实质性的意义
Instead, we have something
相反 我们有一种叫
called semantic materials.
语义素材的东西
Now, if you're familiar with
如果你熟悉
semantic colors, you know that
语义色彩的话
they're named after where
就知道它们的命名
they're used, not necessarily
取决于其使用的地方
what they look like.
而不在于它们看起来像什么
Same thing for semantic
语义素材也是这样
The menu material, for example,
例如 菜单素材
will always look like system
会一直看起来像
contextual menus, regardless of
系统环境菜单
light versus dark.
不论是浅色还是深色模式
And in Mojave, we're introducing
在 Mojave 中 我们引进了
a bunch more semantic materials
更多的语义素材
so that you can always use the
这样你就总可以
right one for your specific use
在特定用例下
case.
使用正确的素材
In fact, these semantic
其实 这些语义素材
materials are now our preferred
是现在我们使用素材时
way of using materials and we're
喜欢用的方法
deprecating these non-semantic
我们淘汰了一些非语义素材
materials like light, dark,
如浅色 深色
medium light, and ultra dark.
中浅色 或者极深色
If you're using one of these
如果你正在用这些素材
materials, now is a great time
那你最好赶快
to go ahead and switch over to a
切换到一个适用于
semantic material that's right
你的用例的
for your use case.
语义素材中
Just to give you an idea of
现在给你大概展示一下
where we're using these semantic
在整个系统里 我们会在哪里
materials across the system,
使用这些语义素材
here's the Finder using the
这是“访达”使用的
title bar and sidebar materials.
标题栏和侧边栏素材
Here's Mail using the header
这是“邮件”使用的标头视图
view and content background
和内容背景素材
Here's our Chameleon Wrangler
这是《Chameleon Wrangler》App
app using the
所使用的
underPageBackground material.
页面背景素材
And here's system preferences
这是系统偏好设置
using the window background
所使用的窗口背景素材
Now, of course this window
现在 关于这个
background material, as you've
窗口背景素材
probably heard, is one of these
你大概有所耳闻
special desktop-tinted materials
它是 Mojave 里新的特殊的
new in Mojave.
桌面着色素材之一
And the way these work is they
而它们运作的方法
pick up a slight tint from the
就是基于窗口在屏幕上的位置
desktop picture based on the
从桌面图片中挑出
window's location onscreen.
一小块色彩
And the idea here is to help
这里的目的是要
your window blend in with the
将你的窗口融入
windows on the rest of the
系统里其他部分的窗口
Again, the easiest way to get
那么 要得到这些根据桌面着色的素材
one of these desktop-tinted
最简单的方法
materials is to use the
就是使用 NSWindow
automatic support in NSWindow,
NSScrollView  NSTableView
NSScrollView, NSTableView, and
和 NSCollectionView 中的
NSCollectionView.
自动支持
The default configurations of
这些对象的
these objects will come with
默认配置与这个
this desktop-tinted effect.
桌面着色效果同时进行
You can also configure NSBox to
你也可以通过设置 NSBox
get these materials by setting
获取这些素材
its type to custom and selecting
只需要把它的类型设为自定义
one of these fill colors.
并选择其中的一个填充色彩即可
It'll use the corresponding
它会使用相应的
NSVisualEffectView material.
NSVisualEffectView 素材
Here's an example.
下面是例子
I'll set my box's type to custom
我会把 boxType 设置为自定义
and then I'll set its fillColor
然后我会将它的填充色彩
to the underPageBackgroundColor.
设定为 underPageBackgroundColor
Of course, I can also use
当然 我也可以用
NSVisualEffectView, I can set
NSVisualEffectView 我可以将
it's material property to the
它的素材属性设置为
underPageBackground material.
underPageBackground 素材
Now, the advantage of using
那么 使用 NSBox 的好处
NSBox is it's back-deployable
就是它可以一直
actually all the way back to
向后兼容至 Leopard
VisualEffectView, on the other
另一方面 visualEffectView
hand, gives you a little more
则给了我们更大的发挥空间
flexibility and I'll give you an
稍后我会给你一个
example of that later.
相关的例子
So, just as a reminder, these
提醒一下
materials will show their
这些素材会在浅色状态下
untinted color in light.
显示未着色的色彩
And in dark, they'll show that
在深色状态下 它们才会显示
desktop-tinting effect.
桌面着色效果
But remember that the tint
但是要记住 着色效果
effect can be disabled.
可能会被禁用
Let me show you why.
原因是这样
So, in Mojave, you can choose an
在 Mojave 中你可以给系统
accent color for the system.
选择一个强调色
And if I switch this over to
如果你将它切换为石墨色
graphite, you'll probably first
你就会看到
notice that all the controls
所有的控件都失去了
lost their colored accents, but
它们的色彩强调
those desktop-tinted materials
但这些桌面着色素材
also lost their tint.
也会失去它们的着色
So, just make sure you're not
所以无论如何要确保
depending on that tint being
你不要指望
there in any way.
桌面着色一直可用
Now, VisualEffectView by default
默认情况下 visualEffectView
will show its material in its
会在像这样的矩形框里
frame rectangle like this.
显示它的素材
And that's pretty great, but
这样挺好的
what if I wanted to show a
但是如果我想要用这个素材
custom UI element with this
显示一个自定义 UI 元素
material, like say a chat
比如说一个这样的对话气泡
How would I do that?
我要怎么做呢
Well, here's one way that seems
下面这种方法看似有用
tempting, but won't work, and
实则行不通
I'll show you why.
我来演示一下为什么
We'll first implement the draw
我们先在 NSView 上
method on NSView and then I'll
执行 draw() 方法
go get my custom chat bubble
然后获取我的自定义对话气泡
BezierPath.
NSBezierPath
And then I'll fill with the
接着我会在路径中执行 fill() 方法
controlBackgroundColor in that
参数为 controlBackgroundColor
path.
好了 如果这么做
it looks something like this and
它就会像这样
it looks pretty good, but if we
看起来还不错
zoom in closely, you'll see that
但如果我们放大看
the bubbles are not getting that
就会发现对话框并没有
desktop-tinting effect that we
我们想要的桌面着色效果
want.
这只是单纯的灰色
So, what went wrong?
这是怎么回事
Well, this effect is provided by
因为 这种效果是由
the Quartz window server like a
Quartz 窗口服务器提供的
lot of our other material
我们许多其他的素材效果也一样
And what this means is it
这就意味着
updates asynchronously from your
它与你的 App 之间
application and this is great
是异步更新的
for performance, but it also
对性能表现来说这样
means that you can't directly
但也意味着你不能直接
draw with that color or get it's
使用那个颜色绘制视图
RGB values.
或是获取它的 RGB 值
Instead, you can use the
相反 你可以用
maskImage property of
NSVisualEffectView 的
VisualEffectView to do something
maskImage 属性来实现类似的效果
maskImage is an optional NSImage
maskImage 是 NSVisualEffectView 中
on VisualEffectView that
一种可选的 NSImage
VisualEffectView will use to
而 NSVisualEffectView 则会利用它来
mask its material, the material
覆盖它的素材
that it shows.
或者说是它显示的素材
And in addition to using
除了使用标准的
standard art-based images, you
基于图案的图像外
can use drawing handler images
你还可以用 Drawing-handler 图像来模拟
material.
素材绘制
Let me show you an example.
下面请看个例子
So, I'll go back to my view,
回到我的视图中
I'll override layout, and I'll
我会重写 layout() 方法
go ahead and add a
继续添加一个
VisualEffectView.
NSVisualEffectView
I'll set its material to the
并将其素材设置为
contentBackground material, and
contentBackground 素材
then I'll create a drawing
接着 我用 NSImage(size: flipped:)
handler image using the NSImage
生成一个初始化程序代码块
size flipped initializer that
来创建一个 Drawing-handler 图像
In it, I'll set the white
这里 我设置成白色
color-- this color doesn't
但什么颜色并不重要
really matter as long as its
只要它是不透明的就行
opaque.
之后 我会继续填充
with my path.
我的路径
Then I'll set that image ask the
然后在 NSVisualEffectView 上
maskImage on my
将该图像设置为 maskImage
All right.
好了
Let's look at it now.
现在我们来看看
Looks a lot better.
看起来好很多
It's desktop-tinted.
它有桌面着色了
And, if we look side by side, we
并且 如果对比起来看
can really see the difference.
我们就能看到不同了
So, this technique works with
那么 这个技巧对任何素材
any material, but just remember
都适用 但是要记住
that only the alpha channel of
只有图像的 Alpha 通道
the image is used for the mask.
被用来制作蒙版
This is similar to template
这点和模板图像类似
And the mask only masks the
而且蒙版仅仅会
material, not any subviews or
覆盖素材 而非任何子视图
other descendent views of the
或 NSVisualEffectView 的
VisualEffectView.
其他继承视图
A common technique is to provide
有一个通用的技术可以
a resizable image for this-- for
为 maskImage 创建一个
the maskImage using the
可调整大小的图像
capInsets and resizingMode
那就是用 NSImage 中的
properties of NSImage.
capInsets 和 resizingMode 属性
And this is really good for
这对性能十分有利
OK.
好 接下来的部分 我将交给 Jeff
Jeff, who is going to talk about
他将和我们谈谈
vibrant blending.
“Vibrant Blending（动态混合）”
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ] Jeff
&gt;&gt; All right.
&gt;&gt; 好的 谢谢 Matt
So, now that we've had a look at
好 现在我们已经
our great materials, I want to
对素材有所了解
cover the things that we draw in
下面我要谈的
front of those materials,
是在那些素材前面的东西
particularly the materials that
特别是那些我们
we use that pull in part of the
通过抓取部分背景
background and provide that
并创建出很棒的
really awesome blur effect.
模糊效果的素材 所以
So, if we revisit our Chameleon
如果我们再进入《Chameleon Wrangler》App
Wrangler application, we have
我们这里已经有了 UI
this UI here, it's our
这是我们的情绪指示器
It's where we go to record how
接着 我们将记录
our various reptiles are
我们各种爬行动物的情绪
And it's in a popover, which
它在一个弹出框中
means that it's automatically
意味着它会
getting that awesome popover
自动地将该弹出框素材
material backing.
作为基底素材
And what we want when we're
而当我们拉下这个基底素材
drawing over this backing
我们想要的是
material is for our content to
我们的内容能够
really stand out on top of that
从各种背景中凸现出来
Something like this.
就像这样
And we do that with an effect
那么 我们就要用一种
that we call vibrancy.
叫做 “Vibrancy（动态化）”的效果
So, what is vibrancy?
那么 什么是 Vibrancy
It's a blending mode that we
它就是一种混合模式
apply to the content that
我们将这种模式运用到内容中
uniformly lightens or darkens
将其背后的内容统一地
the content behind it.
提亮或变暗
It's very similar to a color
这和色彩的减淡或加深
dodge or burn that you might
颇为相似
have seen in your favorite photo
你也许在你常用的照片编辑器
editor or design tool.
或设计工具中见过它
But let's take a closer look.
我们来仔细看看
Here we have a glyph that's
这里我们有一个 Glyph
drawing in about a medium gray,
它是一种中等灰色
about a 50% gray, but at 100%
大概是 50% 的灰色 但完全不透明
And when we apply the vibrant
当我们使用针对深色素材的
blending effect that we use
动态混合效果时
against dark materials, which we
这时我们称之为提亮效果
call a lightening effect, we can
我们能看到
see that it's not that the
其实并不是 Glyph 的
opacity has dropped on our
不透明度下降了
glyph, but we're actually
而是它背后的内容
lightening the content behind it
通过使用
using the lightness of that gray
该灰色值的亮度被提亮了
value.
其实 我们可以看看它
this works on a range of gray
在一系列灰色值上是怎样的
values-- here we have swatches
这里我们有从 0% 到 100% 的
going from 0% to 100% gray, all
灰色色盘 它们都是
totally opaque.
完全不透明的
When we apply our lightening
现在我们使用提亮效果
effect, we can see a number of
我们看到一些
interesting things have
有趣的事情发生了
Down on the bottom right side,
看看右下侧的灰色
we have 100% light, and because
变成了 100% 的亮色
we have added the lightness of
因为我们给内容的背后
white to the content behind, it
添加了白色的亮度
just remains white.
它就变成了这样
There is nowhere further to go.
没有更亮的颜色了
But on the top left where we
但再看左上角
were drawing black, there was no
我们之前绘制的是黑色
lightness to add, which means
无法进行任何提亮了
that it completely disappears.
这意味着它完全消失了
In fact, you wouldn't be able to
事实上 如果不是我在那儿
see it if I didn't have an
画了一个圈儿
outline there.
你都无法看到它
And in-between we can see that
而中间的这些 我们能看到
we have varying degrees of
不同程度的提亮
lightening which we can use to
我们能用这个来
establish a hierarchy of content
在我们的 App 中创建一个
in our application.
内容层级结构
But where does this effect come
但这种效果从哪里来呢
Well, it's our old friend
这时我们的老朋友
NSAppearance, it turns out.
NSAppearance 又派上了用场
We have two special vibrant
我们有两种特殊的
NSAppearance objects,
动态的 NSAppearance 对象
vibrantDark and vibrantLight and
vibrantDark 和 vibrantLight
these are a complete package.
他们都是完整的包
Not only do they include the
不仅包括
exact formula that we use for
我们用作提亮或调暗效果的
that lightening or darkening
精确的公式
effect, but they also have a set
而且还有一套
of control artwork and color
已被设计用在
definitions that have been
该混合模式中的
designed to work great with that
控件图案和颜色定义
But how does your code use it?
但你的代码要如何使用它呢
Well, it's very simple.
其实很简单
In your NSView subclass, you can
在你的 NSView 子类别中
override the allowsVibrancy
你可以重写 allowsVibrancy 属性
property to return true and the
将其返回为真
blending effect is going to
混合效果就会
automatically apply to your
自动应用到
views drawing and also the
你的视图及其
drawing of all of its
所有继承视图的绘制当中
Typically, when you're drawing
特别的是 当你在这个
in this vibrant context, you
动态的环境中绘制时
want to use one of the built-in
你应该采用内置的
label colors, depending on the
LabelColor 之一 取决于
prominence of your content.
内容的突显度
Both vibrantDark and
vibrantDark 和
vibrantLight have great
vibrantLight 都有所有
definitions for all four of
这四种颜色的很好的定义
these colors that allow you to
让你能够
establish that nice hierarchy.
创建很好的层级结构
However, you don't have to use
但是 你也不是必须使用这些颜色
You can use any color that you'd
你可以使用任意你喜欢的颜色
like, but we prefer to use
但是我们最好不要
non-grayscale colors.
使用非灰度颜色
Avoid non-grayscale colors
要避免使用非灰度颜色
because, if you use them, the
因为一旦使用它们
blending effect is going to
混合效果就会
impact the design intent of your
影响到你的颜色的设计意图
color and it's going to wash it
还会用一种你不想要的
out in a way that is not
方式去冲染你的颜色
I'll show you an example of that
稍后我会给你一个例子
So, revisiting our application,
那么 再打开 App
we can go ahead and override
我们可以继续在我们的视图上
allowsVibrancy on our view and
重写 allowsVibrancy
in this case we're going to just
在这里我们就只需要
set it on the view that contains
在包含整个弹出框和
our entire meter in the entire
指示器的视图上设置它
And let's see what that looks
现在我们来看看
Well, our slider looks pretty
好了 滑块看起来很棒
good.
完全如我们所愿
But what happened to the faces?
但是这些表情是怎么回事
They're all washed out.
他们都被冲淡了
And what happened here is that
这是因为
when we set allowsVibrancy on
我们在整个指示器视图上
the overall meter view, not only
设置 allowsVibrancy 时
are we getting the vibrant
我们不仅在该视图上
blending on that view, but also
获得了动态混合
both of these subviews.
还包括了这些子视图
And the fix here is pretty
这里的修复方法很简单
If we localize our definition of
我们只要将
allowsVibrancy to just the part
allowsVibrancy 的定义
that's drawing the slider, we
局部化到绘制滑块的部分
get exactly what we expected.
我们就能获得我们想要的效果
Our slider is drawing vibrantly
我们的滑块是动态绘制的
and the colors in our face
而表情按钮的颜色
buttons look exactly the way
也是我们想要的
When you're drawing vibrantly,
当你进行动态绘制时
typically you'd want to apply
你往往只想要
vibrancy to only the leaf views
在绘制你确实
that are drawing the content
想要动态化的内容的
that you actually want to have
叶视图上
vibrant.
应用 Vibrancy
And, if you have views that are
并且 如果你有绘制
drawing a mix of content, that
混合内容的视图
means that you probably want to
那就意味着你可能想要
break your drawing out into
将你的绘制
separate sibling views that you
分成一些兄弟视图
can use to apply vibrancy at the
以在你想要的粒度层级
granularity that you want.
应用 Vibrancy
Further, you should avoid
而且 你还应该避免
overlapping vibrant and
将动态和非动态的视图相重叠
If you do this, the blending
因为如果重叠了
modes can clash and you might
混合模式将发生冲突
find that some of your content
而一些你的内容就会以
is drawing with a blend mode
一种你并不想要的
that it didn't expect.
混合模式绘制
Further, don't subclass Cocoa
还有 不要通过将 Cocoa 控件
controls just to override
编入子集来
allowsVibrancy.
重写 allowsVibrancy
I mentioned earlier that the
我前面提到过
vibrantLight and vibrantDark
vibrantLight
appearances have been designed
和 vibrantDark 外观是由
with control artwork and colors
专门为混合模式指定的
that were designed specially for
控件图案和色彩所设计的
the blend mode and if you remove
如果你移除这个混合模式
that blend mode, the contrast on
图案的对比度
that artwork is not going to be
就不尽如人意
what you expected because we're
因为我们使用
using the blend mode to provide
该混合模式
a lot of that pop against the
来让它们在素材中突出
material, so you should only
因此你应该
override allows vibrancy if
只在你确实在重写绘制
you're actually overriding
且你知道哪种混合模式
drawing and you know what
或者非混合模式
vibrant blend mode or
适合你正在进行的
non-vibrant blend mode is
绘制的情况下
appropriate for the drawing that
对 allowsVibrancy
you're doing.
进行重写
That's vibrancy.
这就是 Vibrancy
Next, I want to talk a little
接下来 我要谈谈
bit about background styles,
背景风格
specifically the ones that we
特别是我们用于选定的
So, here we have a pretty
这里我们有一个
typical situation in a aqua
在 Aqua Cocoa App 中
Cocoa application.
非常典型的情况
In this case, it's a message
在这个例子中 有一条
from the Mail application and we
取“邮件” App 的消息
can see that when we have a
我们能看到
selection state, we need our
当我们在选定状态时
content inside of this table row
我们需要让这个表格行里的内容反色
to invert to look good against
来在蓝色的选择背景下
that blue selection.
看起来自然
But when we add darkAqua into
但如果我们
the mix, we can see that we
添加了 darkAqua 的话
can't just naively invert our
就能看到我们并不能
content anymore.
单纯进行反色了
That's not going to work
它们看起来不一致
And so we need to describe these
因而我们需要对这些状态
states semantically.
进行语义化描述
Now, if you're familiar with
如果对 Cocoa 熟悉的话
Cocoa, you've probably seen the
你可能已经看到了
NSView.BackgroundStyle enum and
NSView.BackgroundStyle 枚举
that includes a couple of cases,
这其中包括很多个 Case
including light and dark, and
包括浅色和深色
NSTableView sets this
并且 NSTableView 会自动
automatically on the
在 NSTableRowView 和 NSTableCellView 上
TableRowView, TableCellView, and
以及 NSTableCellView 的
also all of the controls that
直接子视图的
are immediate subviews of your
所有控件上自动进行设置
Now, traditionally, we have set
传统情况下
the light background style on
我们会在未被选定行
unselected rows and the dark
设置了浅色的背景风格
background style on selected
在被选定行设置了深色的
But, in the face of this
但是现在 在这个
brand-new, beautiful theme where
背景总是深色的
the background is effectively
全新的漂亮的主题中
always dark, these names don't
以前的命名便
make sense anymore and so we've
不再有意义
renamed them to normal and
所以我们要将它们分别重新命名为
emphasized, respectively.
“normal（普通）”和 “emphasized（强调）”
And these are just more semantic
这些是更为语义化的描述
descriptions that better match
能够更好地匹配这些
the way that these enum cases
应用在新版的 Cocoa App 中
are used in a modern Cocoa
枚举 Case 的方式
We also have some additional
关于背景风格
updates with background styles,
我们还做了一些更新
including that TableView will
包括 NSTableView 现在会
now automatically set that
自动地将背景风格
background style recursively on
循环设置在
all of the controls in your
表格行中的所有控件上
table row, not just the ones
而不仅只是
that are immediate subviews of
你 cellView 中的
your CellView.
直接子视图上
And so, if you've been catching
所以 如果你已经了解了
that background style and trying
那个背景风格
to forward it along to all these
并试着将其应用到所有的子视图上
subviews because you wanted to
因为你想要为布局用一个堆叠视图
use a stacked view or something
或是其他什么东西
for layout, you no longer have
你不再需要
to do that on Mojave.
在 Mojave 上进行这些
That's the applause of somebody
之前手动完成这些的人
who's done this manually.
正在鼓掌
Thank you, I agree.
谢谢 我曾经也是
Further, all four of our label
此外 全部的四种 LabelColor
colors now automatically adapt
都自动适应到了
to the background style, which
背景风格当中
means that you can just set up
这意味着你可以
your content hierarchy once,
创建一次你的内容层级
describe it semantically, and
并语义化地描述它
it's going to look great in both
那么它会在所有的这些环境中
of these contexts.
看起来很棒
You can also use these
你也可以手动使用
emphasized variants manually and
这些强调的变体
I'll give you an example.
举个例子
So, here we have something that
这是一个
looks a little bit like the icon
看起来有点像“访达”里的图标视图
And we've got two labels that
我们有两个标签
are ascribed with label color
它们分别是 labelColor
and secondary label color.
和 secondaryLabelColor
And we want to draw a custom
我们想要在他们后面
selection behind them, so we've
绘制一个自定义选定效果
got this custom Bezier
因此我们有了这个自定义的
path-based selection, maybe
基于 Bezier 路径的选定效果
we're filling it with alternate
我们也许会用另一个
selected control color, and we
已选定控件颜色来填充它
want our labels to match the
我们还想要在这个强调的风格中
primary and secondary variants
将我们的标签与主要变体
in this emphasized style.
及次要变体相匹配
And to get that is very simple.
这很简单
All we have to do is set the
我们需要做的就是
background style to emphasized
在我们的文本域
on both of our text fields and
将背景风格设为强调
they're automatically going to
这样它们会自动地
provide this nice emphasized
提供这个强调变体
And the great thing is that now
很棒的是因为 我们已经将它描述成这样
way, when we switch into Dark
当我们切换为深色模式时
Mode, everything just works.
一切就会如我们所愿
We don't have to do anything
我们不需要
special to support that.
再做什么
One final note on selections.
关于选定 最后要注意一下
The selection material that you
通常你在侧边栏 菜单
commonly see in sidebars, menus,
及弹出框中所见到的选定素材
and popovers now follows the
都跟随着 Mojave 上的强调色 偏好设置
And what that means is that if
这就意味着
you're drawing a custom blue
如果我们绘制一个自定义蓝色
selection, it's not going to fit
选定效果
in.
它会不适应
Instead, you should use
而这时 你要用
NSVisualEffectView.
NSVisualEffectView
It has a special selection
它有一个特殊的选择素材
material just for this and when
适用于这种情况
you use this it's going to
使用 NSVisualEffectView
automatically follow the
该素材就会如你所愿
preference, as you expect.
自动跟随偏好选项
Now, before I get into the
好 最后一部分是重头戏
exciting part, the tips and the
小技巧和方法
tricks, I want to say a couple
但在此之前 我想就
of words about backward
向后兼容谈几句
deployment because we know that
因为我们知道你们中的许多人
many of you, especially on the
特别是使用 Mac 的人
Mac, like to deploy your
喜欢将你们的 App
applications back to previous
向后兼容到之前发布的
releases of macOS and it was
macOS 版本当中
important to us to make sure
要确保你在向后兼容时
that you could adopt Dark Mode
无需进行任何必要的妥协
without necessarily compromising
就可以使用深色模式
on your backward deployment.
这十分重要
And so I'm going to step through
所以我会讲讲几个 API
examine them for backward
检测它们的向后兼容情况
deployment, starting with system
从系统颜色开始
So, here's a sampling of the
所以 这里是我们所支持的
system colors that we support
系统颜色的样本
that are dynamic for the
它们对外观来说是动态的
And what I want to highlight
这里我要强调的是
here is that the ones
高亮为绿色的部分
highlighted in green have been
都至少已经在 10.10 Yosemite 里
available since at least 10.10
出现过了
Yosemite, many of them actually
其中的很多甚至出现得更早
And that means that we think
这就意味着我们希望
that you have a great vocabulary
你可以使用
of colors available to you to
足够多的色彩
describe more or less any UI
几乎可以描述
that you'd like and that all
你所喜欢的任何 UI
supports backward deployment out
并且它们已经直接可以向后兼容了
For custom colors, our modern
就自定义色彩而言
preferred solution for defining
我们现在更偏爱的
them is asset catalogs and these
定义它们的方式是使用素材目录
are available back to 10.13.
而这早在 10.13 就已经可用了
Now, when you do specify dark
现在 如果要给你的任何素材
variants for any of your assets,
添加特定的深色变体
when you back deploy them, those
当你进行向后兼容时
dark variants are safely ignored
这些深色变体都会
on previous versions of the
在之前版本的操作系统上
operating system, so that's a--
被忽略掉
that's a solution that has
所以那就是一个
backward deployment built right
内建的向后兼容解决方案
But if you want to deploy back
但是如果我想要再回去
further than 10.13, you can use
对甚至比 10.13 更早的版本进行兼容
a technique like this where you
你可以用这样的方法
write a custom color property.
创建一个自定义色彩属性
And here we just encapsulate the
这里我们只是封装
availability check to use our
可用性检查
asset catalog color on operating
以在支持素材目录的操作系统上
systems that support it and then
使用我们的素材目录色彩
we can go ahead and put in a
我们可以继续放一个
hardcoded fallback color for
硬编码回调颜色
those older operating systems.
给那些旧的操作系统
Desktop-tinted materials is
桌面着色素材
another great new thing in
是 Mojave 里的另一个新特点
Mojave and if you want to
如果你想要把
address those materials directly
这些素材直接
with VisualEffectView, of course
编为 NSVisualEffectView
that's only available starting
当然这只能在 10.14 上进行
in 10.14, but we've been
但我们已经提供了
providing-- but we have classes
我们已经有一些类提供了
that are providing these
这些素材
materials automatically,
包括 NSWindow
including Window, ScrollView,
NSScrollView 以及 NSTableView
and TableView, which have been
这些在最开始的时候
available since essentially the
就已经提供给大家了
In fact, some of these predate
其实 有的在 macOS 10.0 之前就有了
And so, if you configure them
因此 如果你正确地
correctly, they're going to on
进行设置
previous operating systems show
那么在之前的操作系统上
that special NSColor which looks
他们也会显示出
exactly the way that you would
特殊的 NSColor
expect in previous versions and
正如你所期望的那样
then when you run it on Mojave
接着 如果你在 Mojave 上运行它
you're going to get that
你会自动得到那个素材
And of course NSBox, the custom
当然 NSBox
style that allows you to set a
自定义风格让你能够
fill color, deploys back to
设置一个填充色彩
Leopard 10.5 and so does
并将它向后兼容到 Leopard 10.5 当中
NSCollectionView.
NSCollectionView 也是一样
And this works whether you're
而无论你用的是
using the legacy
之前的 NSCollectionView API
NSCollectionView API or the
还是最新的版本
modern one, although we'd prefer
都不会影响它的工作
that you use the modern one.
当然我们希望你用新的版本
Finally, enabling Dark Mode is
最后是 启动深色模式
generally gated on linking
通常这只是在关联了
against the 10.14 SDK, but, as
10.14 SDK 之后才可以进行
you can see, really, the tools
但是你也看到了 其实
that you need to develop a great
创建一个深色模式下的 App
Dark Mode application aren't
所需要的工具
necessarily specific to the
并非 10.14 SDK 上专有
10.14 SDK and you could have
你完全可以
developed one just using the
用现有的 10.13 SDK
10.13 SDK that you have today.
来进行创建
And so, if you have a situation
那么 如果在某种情况下
where you can't necessarily
你无法更新你的 SDK
update your SDK, we have an
我们有个 Info.plist Key
Info.plist key that you can use
你可以用它
to opt-in to Dark Mode.
进入深色模式
It's called
它叫做 NSRequiresAquaSystemAppearance
and if you set that to NO
如果将其设为 “NO”
explicitly, then that's going to
那么就启动了深色模式
enable Dark Mode even if you're
即使你使用的是
linking on an earlier SDK,
之前的 SDK
although we very strongly prefer
当然我们十分希望你
that you update your SDK.
能更新你的 SDK
It's a far better solution.
因为这是一个更明智的选择
You can also set this key to YES
你也可以将该秘钥设为 “YES”
to disable it temporarily-- and
使其暂时失效
I want to emphasize temporarily.
我想强调一下 只是暂时
This is a key that you can use
你可以利用它给你的时间
to give yourself time to really
来获取一个完美
build a great polished update
支持深色模式的
for supporting Dark Mode.
更新版本
Finally, some tips and tricks.
最后是 一些技巧和方法
First of all, when you're
首先
updating your application, one
当你更新你的 App 时
of the greatest things that you
你可以彻底审查
can do is just audit your use of
你对 NSColor 的使用情况
NSColor just by searching
你只需要通过搜索你的代码库
seeing where you're using it.
并查看你使用它的地方
And you're going to find a
你可能会发现
couple situations that you can
一些可以升级的地方
use to upgrade to make your Dark
来优化你的
Mode experience a lot better.
深色模式体验
And so, for example here, we can
比如说 这里
find places where we're using
我们发现在一些地方
named colors that are not
我们正在使用非动态的
dynamic and also colors that
命名色彩以及一些
have hardcoded components.
包含硬编码的色彩
And when we encounter these
当我们遇到这些情况时
kinds of situations, we can look
可以选择以下
at these and decide one of two
两种方案中的其中一种
One, maybe there is a built-in
第一种 也许有一种
system color that describes what
内建系统色彩
I'm going for and is fully
它能描述我想要的效果
dynamic for the appearance.
在外观中也是完全动态的
Or, two, this is a custom color
或者 第二种
that I think is really important
这是一个自定义色彩
to be specific to my
它对我的 App 来说非常重要
And so the first case is pretty
第一种情况非常简单
We were using black color for
我们之前在这个标签上使用黑色
this label and we can just
之后我们可以
switch that to labelColor and
将其转为 labelColor
that's going to be fully dynamic
这样一来
and do what we expect.
它就是完全动态的了
But in the second case, we might
但在第二种情况中
decide that this color is
我们也许发现这个色彩
actually really special to our
对我们的 App 是十分重要的
app and that's a really great
把它放入素材目录
candidate for moving into the
是一个很好的想法
Not only does this clean up our
我们不仅清理了我们的代码
code because we get all of these
因为我们从代码中
magic numbers out of our code
删掉了这些乱七八糟的数字
and into a data-driven source,
并将它们放入一个数据驱动源中
but we can also then set a dark
我们还可以接着为该色彩
variant for that color and so we
设置一个深色变体
get great Dark Mode support
这样我们就能嵌入
built in.
对深色模式的支持了
Another common source of issues
另一个常见的问题来源是
is offscreen drawing.
离屏绘制
To do offscreen drawing, you
要进行离屏绘制
have to make sure that you're
你需要确保
being sensitive to the
你对外观
appearance and also other
以及其他绘制条件
drawing conditions.
十分敏感
One really common case of this
关于这个 有个情况很常见
is using the NSImage lockFocus
就是用 NSImage 中的 lockFocus API
API to try and draw custom
来试着绘制自定义 NSImage
In this case, we're going to go
这种情况下 我们要
ahead and try and draw this
试着画一个带标记的图像
badged image where we have a
我们有一个基础图像
base image and we're applying a
但由于我们的蜥蜴有了一些新的改变
badge because something new is
我们需要在它的头像上
happening with our lizard.
添加一个标记
And, in this case, we're
在这个例子里
creating an NSImage, calling
我们创建一个 NSImage
lockFocus on it, and then doing
并在它上面调用 lockFocus() 之后进行绘制
And the problem with this is
但问题是
that once we've used lockFocus,
一旦我们使用了 lockFocus
we lose a lot of the semantics.
我们就失去了许多语义
We just have a single bitmap
我们现在只有一个位图表示
And so if the appearance changes
如果外观发生了改变
or if many other conditions
或者其他许多情况改变了
change, including say the
包括我们所说的
backing scale factor because
基底比例系数
you've moved your window from a
比如你将窗口从一个
Retina display to a non-Retina
视网膜显示屏移动到了
display, suddenly this drawing
一个非视网膜显示屏
is going to be stale.
突然 这个绘制就过时了
So, a better solution is to use
所以 更好地解决方法就是
the block-based image-- image
使用基于代码块的 NSImage
initializer, NSImage size
用图像初始化程序
flipped drawing handler.
和 NSImage(size: flipped: )绘制处理程序
And we can just do the exact
你可以直接进行
same drawing that we were doing
与之前一样的绘制
before, but inside of this
但要在这个代码块中进行
And when you assign this kind of
当你给这种图像指定
image to an NSImageView, you're
一个 NSImageView 时
automatically going to have this
这个代码块会自动重新运行
block rerun when the appearance
如果外观发生变化
changes, scale factor changes,
比例系数发生变化
color gamut changes-- anything
色彩空间发生变化
changes, essentially.
其实任何东西发生变化都会导致它重新运行
And so that's great news because
这是一个好消息
if our, say, badge fill color is
因为如果我们的标记填充色彩
a dynamic color, it's going to
是一个动态色彩
always resolve against the
那么它就会一直处理为
correct appearance.
正确的外观
There are a couple of other ways
还有一些其他的方法
that you might be doing
也许能帮你进行
offscreen drawing.
离屏绘制
You might be making custom
你也许在通过
bitmap graphics contexts using
NSGraphicsContext
NSGraphicsContext or
或 CGBitmapContext
CGBitmapContext.
制作自定义位图图形环境
And, depending on what you're
根据你在做的事情
doing, these might also be great
这些也许还可以
candidates for replacing with a
用一个基于代码块的
block-based NSImage.
NSImage 来替换
Further, if you're using the
再者 如果使用参数为 NSRect
NSView cacheDisplay in Rect
的 cacheDisplay() 方法
method to cache your image to a
来将你的图片缓存为
bitmap rep, just be aware that
一个位图表示
this method is not going to
那么要注意
capture some of our more
这种方法并不会捕捉到一些
advanced rendering techniques
我们更进阶的渲染技术
like materials and blurs and
比如素材和模糊
it's also just another way that
如果你的外观改变了
you can produce drawing that
那么这种创建绘图的方法
goes stale when the appearance
也就过时了
changes, so be aware of that.
要注意这点
Here's another situation that
你也许还会碰上另一种情况
If you have an
如果你有一个 NSAttributedString 或
NSTextStorage and you're
NSTextStorage
manipulating those attributes
而你在手动操作这些属性
manually-- say I am in this
在这里 我将我的属性设置为
attributes to just be a
一个带着字体的词典
you might find that this
然后就会呈现出这样的效果
happens.
甚至当你切换为深色模式时
when you switch into Dark Mode
你的文本仍在绘制黑色
and what has happened here?
这里发生了什么
Well, we're missing a foreground
好 我们错过了一个前景颜色属性
color attribute and when the
当文本绘制引擎
text drawing engine encounters a
遇到一系列的
range of attributed strings that
没有一个前景颜色属性的属性字符串时
attribute, it defaults to black.
它便会默认为黑色
And this is what it has always
这就是它一直默认的颜色
defaulted to and it's going to
并且它还会继续
continue to be the default for
为了兼容而保持
compatibility.
默认颜色
So, one way to fix this is to
修复方法之一是
set a foreground color
给我们的一个动态系统色彩
explicitly to one of our dynamic
明确地设置一个前景颜色
system colors, and that's going
接着就会产生我们
to do what you expect.
所期待的效果
But a better alternative is that
但是还有一种更好的方法
if you're doing manual
如果你手动绘制
attributed string drawing, you
属性字符串
should switch to a Cocoa
你应该切换成一个 Cocoa 控件
control, like an NSTextField,
比如一个 NSTextField
which does this for you
它将自动为你完成这些
automatically, or, if you're
或者 如果你正在
manipulating the storage of a
操作一个 textView 的存储
textView, we have new API called
我们有新的 API
performValidatedReplacement on
叫做 performValidatedReplacement
textView that does a nice thing
它会在 textView 上产生不错的效果
If you go ahead and replace a
如果你继续用一个 textView 中的
string with an attributed string
属性字符串
in your textView, it will fill
来代替一个字符串
in any missing attributes with
那它就会用 textView 中的正在使用属性
the typing attributes from the
填充任何缺失的属性
textView, so that way you can go
所以你可以继续
ahead and specify your new
制定新的属性字符串
attributed string without having
而不用手动
to manually merge all your
合并所有的属性
Here's something else that we've
这是我们在一些地方
encountered in a couple places,
所遇到的问题
which is appearances that are
即将外观设置在了
set in Interface Builder.
“Interface Builder（界面构建器）”里
So, if you're going ahead and
如果你继续创建
building and debugging your
并调试你的 App
application and you find that
并且 你的 App 中的某些地方
that just isn't switching, you
并没有切换过来
might have this in your
也许是因为你的界面构建器中有这个
A hardcoded aqua appearance.
硬编码的 Aqua 外观
And it's easy to miss, because
这个很容易被忽视
before today, essentially, you
因为在今天之前
were always running under aqua,
你一直都是在用 Aqua 运行程序
so you didn't notice it.
因此你并没有注意到这点
And the fix for this is easy.
这个修复方法也很简单
If you set this back to the
如果你将这个
Inherited option in the pop-up
在弹出菜单里
menu, your view's going to
设置回“Inherited（继承）”选项
automatically inherit from its
你的视图会自动进行继承它的父辈
An extra special case of this is
还有一个特殊的例子是
NSVisualEffectView.
NSVisualEffectView
It's very likely that if you
如果你在界面构建器里
have a VisualEffectView in
或者在代码里
Interface Builder or even in
有一个 visualEffectView
code, you're setting one of the
你很可能要将两种动态的外观中的一种
two vibrant appearances on it
设置在它上面
and the great news is that in
好消息是
macOS 10.14 this is no longer
在 macOS 10.14 中不再需要这样设置
NSVisualEffectView will
而 NSVisualEffectView 将自动
automatically pick the right
根据他所继承的外观
vibrant appearance based on the
选择正确的动态外观
So, if it inherits darkAqua,
所以 如果它继承了 darkAqua
it's going to choose vibrantDark
它就会选择 vibrantDark
and if it inherits aqua, it'll
而如果继承了 Aqua
choose vibrantLight.
就会选择 vibrantLight
And so the fix for this is easy.
修补方法是这样
In Interface builder, you can
在界面构建器中
set this to inherited and then
你可以将其设置为 “Inherited”
in code you can set the
然后在代码里
appearance to nil or just delete
你可以设置外观 “nil”
your override.
或者删除你的重写
Interface-- speaking of
说到界面构建器
Builder is a great tool for
它是一个很棒的工具
designing and previewing your
可以很好地用来设计和
views visually.
预览你的视图
And so, for example, here I have
比如说 这里有一个视图
a view that is actually a custom
确切地说是一个
view using IB designable.
使用界面构建器设计工具的自定义视图
So, I'm rendering a gradient
我在渲染一个渐变的同时
here and I can see it right here
我就能直接在画布中看到它
And, by default, my canvas is
默认情况下
previewing my custom designable
画布会自动用它当前的外观模式
view using the canvas's
来预览我的自定视图
appearance, in this case dark.
在这里是深色模式
But down at the bottom, we have
但是看看下面
a new toggle that lets you go
这有一个新的切换开关
ahead and set it to the light
你可以把它切换为
appearance so that you can
浅色外观
preview the way that your view
这样你可以预览你的视图
looks in either appearance.
在任意外观中的样子了
And thanks to Interface
多亏了界面构建器
Builder's great support for
对素材目录颜色的
asset catalog colors, we can
良好支持
actually use our custom asset
我们才能使用我们的
catalog colors, which have dark
自定义素材目录颜色
and light variants, and we can
它们有浅色和深色的变体
preview them in the canvas live.
我们可以在画布中实时预览
And if you see there's a little
如果你看到那里有个
arrow button built into that
固定在弹出按钮前的
pop-up button and you can use
小箭头按钮
that to follow it and go
你可以用它来追踪
straight to the definition in
直接进入到你的
your asset catalog, so you can
素材目录的定义中
see live as you're changing it.
你可以实时看到一切变化
And you can do this all without
你可以直接这样做
even building and recompiling.
不用构建或者重新编译
When you do build and run,
当你构建并运行时
you're going to see a new item
你会在你的调试工具栏中
in your Debug Bar and it
看到一个新的东西
produces a menu that allows you
它会产生菜单
to choose the appearance for
让你为你的 App 选择外观
And this is really handy for
这样很方便
previewing your app in various
你可以预览你的 App
appearances without having to go
在各种外观下的样子
and reconfigure your entire
不用重新配置整个系统
Not only can you choose light
你不仅可以选择浅色还是深色
and dark, but you can also
也可以选择
choose the high contrast
高对比度变体
variants and test those as well.
并对它们进行测试
And, if you have a Touch Bar
同时 如果你有一台
Mac, this appears in the
带触控栏的 Mac
expanded Debug Bar as well, so
它也会在你的触控栏出现
you can do this without even
你甚至不需要离开 App
leaving your app to go back to
回到 Xcode 中 就可以
Xcode.
完成这个操作
Finally, I want to talk about
最后 我想谈谈
one last tool in Xcode that is
Xcode 中的一个很棒的工具
really great for debugging your
它非常适合被用于调试
Dark Mode applications.
深色模式下的 App
So, here we have our app and
这是我们的 App
really things are looking pretty
看起来还不错
good.
没什么不对的地方
but I find that when I scroll
但是当我稍微来回
and rubber band a bit, oh, I'm
滑动几下 哦
revealing something that I
我发现了一些
didn't expect.
意想不到的事
There's a light background
这里有一个浅色的背景
hiding back there somewhere, but
隐藏在背后某处
it's hard to see without doing
而如果不是这个小小的滑动
that little scroll gesture.
我们很难看到它
And this is a great case for
这是应该使用 “View Debugger（视图调试器）”
using the View Debugger.
的一个很好的例子
Using the View Debugger's
用视图调试器的
expanded 3D view, the view
扩展 3D 视图
that's drawing unexpectedly is
就能很容易地
really easy to spot.
看到我们那个不太对的视图
And in this case, we can see
在这个例子中 我们能看到
that although our collection
虽然我们的集合视图
view was drawing the background
显示出我们想要的背景
that we expected, the scroll
但在它后面的滚动视图的
view behind it still has a light
背景却仍然是浅色的
And when we select it, we can
我们可以选出这部分
use the Inspector to see how
并用 Inspector 来检查
it's being configured.
它是如何配置的
And in this case, we can verify
在这里 我们可以确定
that, yeah, it's just drawing a
没错 它有一个
hardcoded white color and that's
硬编码的白色
a really easy fix.
这很好处理
The View Debugger has made a
视图调试器在 Xcode 10 中
number of enhancements in Xcode
做了很多优化
10 that are great for debugging
能够很好地调试
Dark Mode applications,
深色模式的 App
including colors.
包括色彩
They can now show you the names
它们现在可以显示出色彩的名字
of colors, both dynamic system
包括动态系统色彩
colors and your asset catalog
和你的素材目录色彩
colors, so you can identify
这样你可以分辨出
where these RGB components are
这些 RGB 成分来自哪里
coming from, and it'll show you
它还会显示你的
the configuration of your view
NSAppearance 视图的配置
for NSAppearance, including the
包括它要绘制的外观
draw with as well as whether
以及在该对象上
there's any local overrides of
是否有任何
NSAppearance on that object.
NSAppearance 的局部重写
So, we have covered an awful lot
好了 我们已经涉及了
of content and so let's rewind
非常多的内容
and make sure that we remember
让我们快速回顾一下
it all.
确保我们能记住
We started off with NSAppearance
我们从 NSAppearance 开始
and leveraging it effectively to
用它顺利地
draw your custom views that
绘制了基于主题的
adapt based on the theme.
自定义视图
Then we learned how to add depth
然后我们学习了如何
and beauty to our UI using our
使用全新的 NSVisualEffectView
new and updated palette of
素材的调色盘
NSVisualEffectView materials.
来增加我们 UI 的深度并美化它
We talked about drawing in a
我们谈到了如何在一些
couple of interesting contexts,
有趣的环境中绘图
both vibrancy and selections,
包括 Vibrancy 和选定
and then we walked through some
之后谈到通过一些方法
of the great ways that Xcode can
Xcode 可以帮你
help you design and debug your
设计和调试你的 App 的
Dark Mode applications.
深色模式
As always, you can go to
你可以像往常一样 前往
developer.apple.com to re-watch
developer.apple.com
the video for this talk and see
再次观看此次讨论会的视频
any related resources and we
也可以观看任何
have labs today.
相关的资源
We have a special Cocoa and Dark
我们今天有个特别的
Mode Lab, it's at 2:00, and not
Cocoa 和深色模式实验室
only will we have Cocoa
在下午 2:00 进行
engineers onsite to help you
届时不仅会有 Cocoa 的工程师
with your code, but we'll also
帮助你解决代码问题
have human interface designers
还有人机界面设计师
onsite to help you with your
帮助你解决
design questions as well.
你的设计问题
So, go get lunch, think about
所以先去吃午饭吧
Dark Mode the entire time, and
思考一下深色模式
then come see us.
然后再来与我们相会
And then, finally, we have an
最后 我们还有一个
additional Cocoa Lab on Friday
额外的 Cocoa 实验室
at 11:00 as well.
在周五上午 11:00
All right.
好的
Thank you very much.
谢谢大家
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]